

RITESH SENGUPTA

UI/UX Designer

https://riteshsengupta.github.io



SUMMARY

Ritesh is a self-taught UX designer with more than a decade of experience focused on creating intuitive and easy-to-use experiences for web and hand held devices. He is Certified ScrumMaster® worked closely with the Product team in an Agile/Scrum workflow to design visually-compelling and highly-usable mobile and web applications. Over a journey as a designer he learnt many techniques and proficiency in User Centered Design. He has experience working in all stages of a product's lifecycle, from conception to design, development and validation.

He usually follows seven steps to achieving the design process flow before deliver/launch. Empathize > Research & Analysis > Information Architecture > Wireframes > Prototypes > Visual Design > Usability Testing.

EXPERIENCE

Nomura Research Institute Financial Technologies, June 2007 - present

Manager - Creative Practice // www.nrifintech.com

- Fully hands-on. collaborate with agile, multi-disciplinary teams to evaluate the feasibility of proposed features and create phased approaches to development.
- Communicate design decisions to stakeholders through low to medium fidelity wireframes and detailed interaction specifications.
- Rapidly build prototypes, develop websites and enterprise application interaction flow and work closely with developers to implement designs.
- Lead UI/UX team through iterative lifecycle of research design development testing.

Radiance Software, Feb 2006 - June 2007

Sr. Web Designer

- Visualise, create mockups and convert into Html and CSS.
- Incorporate into mostly ecommerce/oscommerce and corporate websites.

Citytech Software, July 2005 - Feb 2007

Web Developer // www.citytechcorp.com

Visualise, create mockups and convert into Html and CSS.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Master of Business Administration (IT), April 2016

Sikkim Manipal University

Bachelor of Commerce (Hons), April 2002

Calcutta University

CERTIFICATION

Certified Scrum Master ®

SCRUM ALLIANCE® | Certificant ID: 000722700, Till: 30 Nov 2019

UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, Development, pursuing Udemy

Advanced Certificate Course on Multimedia & Web Development Technology, 2003 MTDRC, Jadavpur University (ZedCA)

PERSONAL DETAILS

SkypeLanguageLocationritesh.senguptaEnglish, Bengali & HindiKolkata, India

SKILLS

UX Research

Business Analysis & Empathy Workshop

Persona Development

User Journey Map - Define Touch Point

Task Analysis

Usability Testing

UX Design

Ideation

Pen and Pencil

Wireframing

Color and Typography

Visual Design

Interaction Design

Prototyping

TOOLS

Design

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Prototyping

Moqups

Axure RP 7

Adobe XD

InVision

Sketch

DEVELOPMENT & UTILITIES

HTML5 / CSS3

SCSS / LESS

Bootstrap

Cross Browser & Device

Materializecss

CVS, GIT, VS Code, Notepad ++

TEAM MANGEMENT

Work Review & Follow up

Team Collaborations

Jira & Confluence